Guide to the Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale gay and lesbian alumni records
1982-1998
RU 956
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
(4 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, drafts of constitution and bylaws, newsletters, and news clippings documenting the activities of the Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni (GALA).
Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 8-C-1 (YRG 8-C-1), Records of organizations open to all Yale alumni.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were a gift of Corey Alan Friedlander, 2004; Dennis W. Mack, 2010.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See inventory for details.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni (GALA) was established in 1983. It sponsors social and educational events, supports the goals and activities of campus gay and lesbian organizations, and promotes an atmosphere of understanding and cooperation among its members and the entire Yale community.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, drafts of constitution and bylaws, newsletters, and news clippings documenting the activities of the Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni (GALA).
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Gay clubs; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni; Yale University -- Alumnae and alumnae -- Societies, etc.
- Yale Gay and Lesian Alumni (GALA) records and files of Corey Friedlander, circa 1984-1987; Accession 2004-A-202
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023.
  - Yale bulldog banner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - GALA alumni, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - GALA/CSC, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yale alumni magazine, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - GALA reunion correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter 1, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter 2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter 3, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reunion #1, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - GLAD day rally, GALA newsletter, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - National Yale GALA correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - GALA 1984 reunion plans #2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yale GALA (parts 1 and 2), 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - GALA, correspondence, planning, Yale alumni magazine, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - GALA in the news, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - AIDS prevention week, Yale GALA, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Yale GALA calendar, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - GALA list updates and dues, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - GALA dues and donations, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Yale alumni fund, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Proposed certificate of incorporation, complete Yale GALA list, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - NEGALA, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - YALE GALA alumni, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence to Corey Friedlander, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - GLC newsletter, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Yale GALA alumni reunion posters (2), 1984 June 1-3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Computer files (Reel 3)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
- Yale Gay and Lesbian Alumni (GALA) records, 1982-1998; Accession 2010-A-076
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2034.
  - Administrative records and correspondence, 1983-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Boston/Washington, D.C. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting minutes, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Newsletters, 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Other gay and lesbian alumni groups, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Press, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)